# **Owen Cao**

72 Nelson Street, Auckland Website: HelloOwen.com Mobile: 021 0815 1033

Email: owen.cao@hotmail.com

## Summary

Software Engineer with three years' experience implementing Web Application in Java for top IT companies; designed new API for Cisco Common Identity used by four million users; reduced critical flow's response time by 42% by an optimized data organisation and a new SDK.

### Skills

- Java Web Development (Spring, Restful API, JSON, Tomcat, MySQL, Linux).
- Testing (Mockito, TestNG, JMeter, Jenkins).
- Security, Identity Management (OAuth 2.0, SAML, LDAP).
- · Agile/Scrum methodology.

## Experience

#### **Applications Developer, Oracle**

December 2014 – June 2015 | Suzhou, China

Scrum team member in Oracle Fusion HCM team. Oracle Fusion HCM (Human Capital Management) is a leading solution in HR Software market, designed and developed on Oracle Fusion Middleware.

- Oracle Fusion Middleware 11g: Build Application with ADF Certification.
- Performed daily regression testing and fixed bugs.
- Developed new features for Migration Service Module in Java and ADF.

#### Software Engineer, Cisco

July 2013 - November 2014 | Suzhou, China

Scrum team member/User Story owner in Cisco OAuth team. Cisco OAuth, the authorization component in Cisco Common Identity Service, provides a standard way for resource owners to grant client applications access to the owners' webbased resources.

- Designed and implemented RESTful Token Management API using Jersey.
- Developed Test Automation using Mockito, TestNG, Jenkins and Git along with other team members.
- Improved storage performance by new structure and SDK, 90% line of Response Time of Authorization Code Flow was reduced by 42%.

#### Software Engineer, Aegis

July 2012 - March 2013 | Nanjing, China

Aegis is a startup IT company working to provide customer satisfaction monitoring service to organizations. This service helps to collect web pages with some certain key words from Internet news and BBS, and then analyze data to enable businesses to better measure customer satisfaction.

- Designed and implemented comments parser in Java and JSON.
- Optimized content extraction algorithm, the average recognition rate is 90%.
- Developed BBS breadcrumb parser with Java and HTML Parser.

#### Software Engineer, IBM

April 2012 – June 2012 | Shanghai, China

Worked as an intern in IBM VOCA team. VOCA (Voice of Customer Analytic) is a service designed to help organizations mine data from call transcripts, emails and survey results, and then analyze that data to better gauge customer sentiment and improve marketing.

- Designed sentiment analysis dictionaries and data extraction rules.
- Implemented extraction module in Java & AQL (Annotation Query Language).
- Developed the statistics page for the annotators result in JSP.

### Education

M.Eng., Software Engineering, Nanjing University, 2013. B.Eng., Software Engineering, Nanjing University, 2011.

- · People's Scholarship.
- Academic Competition Scholarship.
- Top 10, National Software Design Competition for College Students (Awarded Excellent Prize, out of 400 projects).